Maira Prado

Product Designer

Contact

(929)766-9535 mairapradol@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/maira-prado www.mairaprado.com

Summary

Product Designer with over 5 years of experience, blending strong design and analytical skills. Pioneered the transformation of the ordering experience for Transfer and Edge Appliances at Google Cloud, driving a significant sales surge and enabling self-service capabilities across 31 countries. Additionally, served as the main designer of a crucial Google Cloud feature, bridging a significant market gap. Well-versed in Figma and other design tools, prototypes, and usability studies. Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies (CPACC). Multilingual, speaking English, Portuguese, and Spanish.

Experience

UX Designer | Google | 2021-2023

- Designed the end-to-end self-service experience for Google Cloud's two appliances, driving a significant increase in sales and enabling self-service functionality across 31 countries.
- Created prototypes for team feedback and to facilitate usability testing.
- Collaborated across four teams to design and launch a key feature for Google Cloud, ensuring seamless integration and product functionality.
- Bolstered engineering by supporting implementation, participating in two pre-launch bug hunts, and ensuring postlaunch product success.
- Enhanced Google's educational content by conducting user research and implementing strategies to improve accessibility for individuals with dyscalculia; potentially benefiting up to 6% of the global population.
- Created two surveys to refine Google's internal educational materials, enhancing content quality and engagement.
- Presented about dyscalculia to two teams to create awareness and also delivered a presentation at a Google conference, reaching an audience of 50 people and furthering inclusivity efforts.

Product Designer | Freelance | 2019-2024

- Using user surveys, personas, competitive analysis, and user stories to gather data and inform design decisions based on user feedback.
- Creating user flows, diagrams, sketches, wireframes, brand identities, style guides, mockups, and prototypes, and conducting usability testing to verify that designs precisely meet user needs.
- Providing expert consulting services in UX design, enhancing usability and design quality across multiple platforms, significantly improving user satisfaction and digital presence.

Tools & Methodologies

Figma, Sketch, InVision, Adobe Creative Cloud, Miro, UsabilityHub, GitHub, Atom, Jira, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Prototypes, Mockups, User Flows, Wireframes, Style Guides, Navigation Structures, Affinity Diagrams, Usability Studies, Task Analysis, User Personas, Competitive Analysis, Card Sorting, A/B Testing, WCAG 2.2.

Education

Google | 2021-2022 UX Design Specialization

Google | 2022

Accessibility Foundation Certification (FAKC)

IAAP | 2021

Certified Professional in Accessibility Core Competencies (CPACC)

Bloc | 2019-2020 Design Program

Tuiuti | 2005-2011 Law School

Community contribution

- Delivered a presentation at Google's Accessibility Internal Conference on 'Getting Started with Designing for Accessibility'.
- Presented at Google's UX conference on equitable UX design careers, emphasizing the inclusion of diverse backgrounds.
- Played a pivotal role in volunteer efforts such as the Code Nation Hackathon and robotics workshops, supporting 400 underrepresented youth in tech.
- Organized the Day of the Dead celebration at Google, promoting workplace diversity and cultural awareness among over 300 employees.
- Served as a UX and coding mentor for over 4 years, guiding and supporting emerging designers in the field.